The benefits of regular exercise are well documented but there’s a new bonus to add to the ever-growing list.
经常锻炼的好处早已得到充分证实，而现在，这份不断加长的清单上又可以添上一项新的好处。
New research found that middle-aged women who were physically fit could be nearly 90 percent less likely to develop dementia in later life, and if they did, it came on a decade later than in less sporty women.
新研究发现，中年时身体素质好的女性日后患痴呆的可能性或许会低近90%；即使患病，发病时间也比运动较少的女性晚十年。
Lead researcher Dr. Helena Horder, of the University of Gothenburg in Sweden, said: “These findings are exciting because it’s possible that improving people’s cardiovascular fitness in middle age could delay dementia or even prevent them from developing it.”
首席研究员、瑞典哥德堡大学的海伦娜·霍德博士说：“这些发现令人振奋，因为在中年时提高人们的心血管健康水平，有可能延缓痴呆的发生，甚至预防他们患上痴呆。”
For the study, 191 women with an average age of 50 took a bicycle exercise test until they were exhausted to measure their peak cardiovascular capacity.
在这项研究中，191名平均年龄为50岁的女性进行了自行车运动测试，一直骑到筋疲力尽，以测量她们的心血管能力峰值。
The average peak workload was measured at 103 watts.
测得的平均峰值负荷为103瓦。
A total of 40 women met the criteria for a high fitness level, or 120 watts or higher.
共有40名女性达到高体能水平的标准，即峰值负荷达到120瓦或以上。
A total of 92 women were in the medium fitness category; and 59 women were in the low fitness category, defined as a peak workload of 80 watts or less, or having their exercise tests stopped because of high blood pressure, chest pain or other cardiovascular problems.
共有92名女性属于中等体能类别；59名女性属于低体能类别，其定义为峰值负荷在80瓦及以下，或因高血压、胸痛或其他心血管问题而中止运动测试。
These women were then tested for dementia six times over the following four decades.
在随后的四十年里，这些女性接受了六次痴呆检测。
During that time, 44 of the women developed dementia.
在此期间，其中44名女性患上了痴呆。
Five percent of the highly fit women developed dementia, compared to 25 percent of the women with medium fitness and 32 percent of the women with low fitness.
高体能女性中有5%患上了痴呆，相比之下，中等体能女性中这一比例为25%，低体能女性中为32%。
“However, this study does not show cause and effect between cardiovascular fitness and dementia; it only shows an association.
“不过，这项研究并未显示心血管健康与痴呆之间存在因果关系；它只显示了二者之间的关联。
More research is needed to see if improved fitness could have a positive effect on the risk of dementia and also to look at when during a lifetime a high fitness level is most important.”
还需要进一步研究，看看提高体能是否会对痴呆风险产生积极影响，同时也要研究人一生中什么时候保持高体能水平最为重要。”
She also admitted that a relatively small number of women were studied, all of whom were from Sweden, so the results might not be applicable to other groups.
她也承认，参与研究的女性人数相对较少，而且全都来自瑞典，因此研究结果可能并不适用于其他群体。